Matthew Sainsbury-Dale

6/12 Pleasent Av. \diamond Wollongong, NSW 2500 0437 108 424 \diamond msdale@uow.edu.au

PROFILE

A hard-working statistician with a focus on spatial and spatio-temporal statistics. Excellent analytic skills, with well-developed programming abilities primarily centred around the use of R and C++, but also using Python and Julia. Experience working individually and in a team environment.

EDUCATION

University of Wollongong

March 2015 - November 2019

· Bachelor of Mathematics Advanced (Honours; Class I)

University of Wollongong

March 2020 - Present

· PhD in Statistics: "Modelling Complex Spatial and Spatio-Temporal Data". Under the supervision of Dr. Andrew Zammit-Mangion and Prof. Noel Cressie.

RESEARCH OUTPUTS

Journal Articles

- · Sainsbury-Dale, M., Zammit-Mangion, A., and Cressie, N. (In prep.). Modelling, Fitting, and Prediction with Non-Gaussian Spatial and Spatio-Temporal Data using FRK.
- · Cressie, N., Sainsbury-Dale, M., and Zammit-Mangion, A. (In press). Basis-Function Models in Spatial Statistics. *Annual Review of Statistics and its Applications*.

Software

- · Co-author of the R package FRK, available on CRAN.
- · Author of the R package testarguments, available on CRAN.

EXPERIENCE

School of Mathematics and Applied Statistics (SMAS)

March 2019 - Present

Tutor

- · Mathematics and statistics tutor for several subjects.
- · Created the official subject notes for an Honours-level statistics subject.

Centre for Bioinformatics and Biometrics (CBB) Intern

November 2018 - March 2019

- · Analysed single-site trials for the National Variety Trials (NVT) program.
- · Conducted research and produced a substantial statistical report for the CBB.

Centre for Big Data Research in Health (CBDRH)

June 2018 – November 2018

Research assistant

- · Developed course material for the Masters level subject 'Machine Learning and Data Mining' at UNSW. This course covered many aspects of machine learning and data mining. The methods were implemented with Python, and the tutorials were held on the Jupyter notebook platform.
- Reviewed course material for a third year statistical modelling subject. Responsibilities included ensuring material was coherent and statistically sound, as well as debugging code.

KEY SKILLS

Programming Highly proficient with R, and experience using Julia, Python, and C++.

Able to quickly learn and use unfamiliar programming languages and

packages.

Statistical Modelling Firm knowledge of a wide range of statistical models and inferential

methods.

Collaboration Experience collaborating with peers using version control software, such

as Github and Dropbox.

Data Mining Exposure to frequently used data mining topics including clustering,

classification, and regression algorithms. Use of R and Python to apply

these methods.

Personal Traits Excellent written and oral communication skills. Leadership qualities

built through various leadership roles including High School Captain and Captain of representative sport teams. Experience working in team situations whilst also able to work alone. Highly self-motivated learner.

RELEVANT COURSES

Core Courses

Advanced Data Analysis

Linear & Generalised Linear Models

Statistical Inference

Sample Surveys & Experimental Design

Applied Bayesian Methods

Estimation & Hypothesis Testing

Other Courses

Data Mining & Knowledge Discovery Applied Mathematical Modelling I, II, III

Complex Variables & Group Theory

Differential Equations I, II, III Multivariate & Vector Calculus

Linear Algebra

REFEREES

• Dr. Andrew Zammit-Mangion, Senior Research Fellow at the National Institute for Applied Statistics Research Australia (NIASRA). Contact details available upon request.